Arun Mutkule

Near Gajanan Mandir Shivsena office Tapikir Nagar, Alandi, Pune, Maharastra 412105 • 8055643220 • arun.mutkule@yahoo.com

Professional Summary

IT Specialist with 4 years and 2 month of extensive experience in linux, Docker, aws cloud, Middleware and Operating System (Linux System). Capable of handling the client's needs by translating them into appropriate technical solutions and providing motivation, guidance to both colleagues and clients. Reliable self- starter with the ability to plan, design, implement, and manage small, medium, and large systems. Good communication skills, interpersonal skills, self-motivated, quick learner. Possess strong troubleshooting, problem solving and analytical skills.

Skill

O/S : Linux and Windows, CentOS

RedHat : DHCP, FTP, DNS, APACHE, NIS, NFS, SAMBA, ACL, LDAP, YUM

Cloud : AWS – (S3, EC2, IAM, ELB, VPC, cloud Watch, CDN, Route 53)

Containerization : Docker **SCM tool** : GitHub

Build Server : Jenkins, CI/CD

RDBMS : MySQL

Application Server : Apache Tomcat,
DevOps Tools : GitHub, Jenkins
Scripting : shell scripting
Configuration Management : Ansible

Email client software : MS-Outlook, thunderbird

Work History

System Engineer 1 /8/2019 to Currents

EPPS PVT LTD – pune, MH,

- configuration server & diagnosis DHCP,FTP,SAMBA,NFS,APACHE,SSH,TELNET,configuration YUM server,
- Built and maintained a network infrastructure consisting of Windows, Linux and virtual products.
- installation network printer and troubleshoot
- Configuration Apache tomcat in eclipse server.
- Handling Os tickets and Bugzilla tools
- Handle cloud server and monitoring.
- Remote tools VNC, Any desk, putty, RDP
- Create user and give to access
- installation & configuration mailing client software (thunderbird and outlook)
- Provided documentation on start-up, shut down and first level troubleshooting of processes to help desk staff.
- Configure Jenkins server and take build
- Configure Ansible and push software and install using Ansible
- Handling firewall and give to access to user and permission to access website

Desktop Support Engineer, 06/2017 to 08/2019 **Brainbees Solution Pvt Ltd** – Pune, MH

- Managed and monitored all installed systems and infrastructure to ensure the highest level of availability.
- Installed, configured, tested and maintained operating systems, application software and system management tools.
- Resolved issues related to operational components for Local Area Networks, Wide Area Networks and voice systems.
- Managed installation, upgrade and deployment projects and provided on-site direction for network engineers.
- Built and maintained a network infrastructure consisting of Windows, Linux and virtual products.
- Provided 2nd and 3rd level technical support and troubleshooting to internal and external clients.
- Planned and implemented upgrades to system hardware and software.
- Recommended architectural improvements, design solutions and integration solutions.
- configuration server & diagnosis DHCP,FTP,SAMBA,NFS,APACHE,SSH,TELNET,configuration YUM server,
- installation & configuration mailing client software(thunderbird and outlook)
- installation network printer and troubleshoot
- AWS (EC2,IAM,ELB,SNS,CLoudWatch,Cloud Front,)
- work on remote(RDP,AnyDesk)

Desktop Support Engineer, 12/2016 to 06/2017 **Satyajeet India Enterprises Pvt. Ltd.** – Pune, MH

- Provided documentation on start-up, shut down and first level troubleshooting of processes to help desk staff.
- Independently designed and executed company catalog for infrastructure support and development.
- Diagnosed and troubleshoot UNIX and Windows processing problems and applied solutions to Increase company efficiency.
- Managed firewall, network monitoring and server monitoring both on- and off-site.
- Configuration outlook and client software
- Troubleshoot hardware and printer problem
- Create user and give to access

Desktop Support Engineer, 08/2015 to 09/2016

Siddhivinayak computer services – Aurangabad, MH

- Diagnosed and troubleshoot UNIX and Windows processing problems and applied solutions to increase company efficiency.
- Implemented company policies, technical procedures and standards for preserving the integrity and security of data, reports and access.
- Proposed technical feasibility solutions for new functional designs and suggested options for performance improvement of technical objects.

- Provided documentation on start-up, shut down and first level troubleshooting of processes to help desk staff.
- configuration outlook and install necessary software and on call support desktop troubleshooting

Education

High School: 10th 2006

Jay Bharat Vidhyalaya - Jawala (b.k) Hingoli MH

High School: 12th 2008

Rabindranath Tagore art & science college – Parbhani MH

Bachelor of Science: BCA, 2013

NALANDA MANAGEMENT & COMPUTER SCIENCE COLLEGE - Aurangabad, MH

Master of Science: MCA, 2015

G H Raisoni College of Engineering & Management - Pune, MH

Place- Arun Mutkule

Date-